玄黄端现 太极混沌如鸡蛋
ln the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的
giving birth to an endless, expanding existence...
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
现在所见超乎我们的想象
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了客观认知极限
beyond the limits of our existence...
那地方我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe."
太空中的大哥大都是巨无霸
The biggest things in space are gargantuan beasts.
个个都是其星系门类里的巨子
Each one is a heavyweight in its galactic division.
宇宙是个难以想象的大地方
The universe is an unimaginably large place.
它大到人类确实难以领悟那种尺度的东西
lt's so big it's really hard for human beings...to actually comprehend things of these size scales.
地球上和宇宙间 以大为美
On Earth and in the universe, size matters...
然而它关乎不同的前途
but it matters in different ways.
太空中 大不见得好
ln space, bigger is not necessarily better.
往往是优胜者生活奢侈 英年早逝
And oftentimes, the winners live large and die young.
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制:春树  字幕来源:五羊皮  调校:御雪寒狼  招募Q号:76846146
[历史频道] 第二季 第十六集 宇宙巨物
[History Channel] The UniverseⅡ 16of19 Biggest.Things.in.Space
它们是宇宙间的珠峰
They're the Mount Everests of the cosmos.
天文学家们如狗仔队那样瞄着自己的望远镜
Astronomers aim their telescopes at them like paparazzi...
渴望捕捉到它们每个动作的图像
eager to capture images of their every movement.
它们是宇宙间的大哥大
They are the biggest things in the universe...
它们的规模简直难以置信
and their sizes are truly mind-boggling.
对于宇宙间的巨无霸来说 幸运的是
The good thing about being huge in the universe...
宇宙比你还要巨大
is that the universe is even huger than you are...
所以 有足够的空间去延展
so there's plenty of space to stretch out...
将度量的尺度
and get your size measured...
给一探究竟的智能文明
among intelligent civilizations that are having a look.
你在开始研究天文时 首先发现的
The first thing you find out...when you start studying astronomy...
一切都乖乖真大
is how darn big everything is.
你研究的几乎每一样东西
Almost everything you're studying...
都远远超出人类的尺度
is so far beyond any kind of human scale...
那是我们日常生活中从未碰到过的
that we're ever going to encounter in our normal lives.
宇宙充满了庞然大物
The universe is brimming with gigantic objects.
在我们的太阳系里
Within our own solar system...
地球是第五大行星
Earth is the fifth biggest planet...
不过它比起太空中最大的东西
but it's a hundred million billion times smaller...
要小上十亿亿倍
than the largest stuff in space.
那么谁又拥有宇宙间大哥大美誉呢？
So what holds the coveted title...as the biggest thing in the universe?
多数天文学家认为是宇宙网络
Most astronomers agree it's the cosmic web...
星系间超星系团的无边无际的鹰架
an endless scaffolding of superclusters of galaxies...
四周是暗物质
surrounded by dark matter...
一种无形而神秘的物质形态
an invisible and mysterious form of matter...
占有宇宙90%的物质
that accounts for 90 percent of the universe's mass.
宇宙间的大哥大
The largest thing in the universe...
你甚至会怀疑 它是否就是那回事
you might even wonder if it's a thing at all...
是暗物质构成的网
it's a web of dark matter...
在宇宙间滥竽充数
that fills the volume of the universe.
暗物质是我们无法看见的物质
Dark matter is this matter that we can't even see.
它不发出任何光
lt doesn't emit any light...
然而 却遍布宇宙
but it is filled throughout the universe...
是其中的结构
and there's structure in it.
暗物质是神秘兮兮的东西
Dark matter is something much more mysterious...
超乎多数人的了解
than most people know.
确实 构成我的物质
Literally, the stuff that makes me up...
暗物质是毫不搭边的
dark matter isn't made of that.
我不认为你闻得出它
l don't think you could smell it...
我不认为你摸得到它
l don't think you could touch it.
它只有引力
lt simply has gravitational attraction.
暗物质的宇宙网络要能够看得见
The cosmic web of dark matter becomes visible...
前提是要有物体填补其中
when looking at the objects that fill it.
这个宇宙网络确实就像是
This cosmic web really is almost like...
三维的蜘蛛网
a three-dimensional spider"s web.
在所有漩涡的中心
At the very center of all the vortexes...
都存在着超星系团
there are the superclusters...
数千个星系组成的星团
clusters of thousands of galaxies...
于是星系间的丝网将它们连接起来
and then filaments of galaxies connect them...
覆盖了整个浩瀚的宇宙
all the way across the volume of the universe.
这些网状结构的节点上的最深厚最强大的引力
The deepest, strongest gravity...at the intersections of these weblike structures...
就是无处不在的气体瀑布
is where all the gas falls...
那里就是星系以及星系团形成的地方
and that's where galaxies form... clusters of galaxies form.
但是宇宙网络究竟有多大呢？
Butjust how big is the cosmic web?
如果银河系如罂粟种子般大小
lf the Milky Way galaxy were the size of a poppy seed...
那么有形的宇宙 我们所看到的一切
then the observable universe, everything we can see...
就会玫瑰碗球场那般大
would be about the volume of the Rose Bowl stadium.
现在 全部装进宇宙网络里
Now, that entire volume is filled with a cosmic web...
超星系团联系在一起
superclusters linked together...
从宇宙的一头到另一头
from one side of the universe to the other.
宇宙网络的起源依然不明朗
The origins of the cosmic web remain uncertain...
但是 科学家认为其最早的种子在大爆炸
but scientists think its initial seeds were planted...
即宇宙的诞生时已经种下
in the Big Bang, the beginning of the universe.
大爆炸期间
During the Big Bang explosion...
整个宇宙突然爆发 基本上
the whole universe blew up, essentially...
膨胀非常迅速
and expanded very rapidly...
所以宇宙的物质网络
so the cosmic matterweb...
包含了大爆炸期间创造的所有原始物质
contains all of the original matter...that was created during the Big Bang...
产生了我们今日所见的极其庞大的结构
just blown up into the very, very large structures...that we see today.
科学家正致力于描绘出遍布整个宇宙的宇宙网络
Scientists are actively trying to map out the cosmic web...which spans the entire universe.
手段之一就是观察高温的X射线发光气体
One way is to look at hot, x-ray-emitting gas...
以及它是如何被暗物质的引力所控制的
and how it's contained...by the gravity present in the dark matter.
另一个手段就是观察所谓的引力透镜
Anotherway is to look at something called...
在那里光会被宇宙网络的引力给扭曲
gravitational lensing, where light is bent...by the gravity of the cosmic web...
这样我们就能够看到宇宙网络的轮廓
and so we're able to sort of see the outlines...of that cosmic web...
基于它扭曲其背后的光
by the way it distorts the light that's behind it.
宇宙网络基本上包含了宇宙间的一切
The cosmic web...basically contains everything in the universe...
但是 有些科学家质疑
but some scientists question...
它是否就是科学意义上的最大的物体了
whether it's technically the largest object...
因为这网络并不是连绵不断地包括了整个空间
because the web isn't continuously connected...throughout space.
宇宙物质网络其实并不是宇宙间
The cosmic matterweb is not actually the largest...
最大的引力约束体
gravitationally bound object in the universe...
因为整个宇宙间的物质
because all the matter in the universe...
散布得非常广泛
has expanded so vastly...
以至于引力并不足以将其集中到一个区域
the force of gravity is not enough...to keep it together in one area...
然而超星系团实际上是引力约束
whereas superclusters of galaxies...are actually gravitationally bound...
也就是说它们具有足够的质量
meaning that they have enough mass...
产生足够的引力 将它们结合在一起
to produce enough gravity to hold them together...
穿越时间长河
over the passage of time.
天文学家并没有可靠的判断
Astronomers don't have a firm estimate...
不过宇宙网络有可能是无数超级集群构成的
but the cosmic web could be made up...of hundreds ofthousands of superclustered complexes.
这些就是通过引力结合在一起的
These are mega collections of galaxies...
庞大星系集群
gravitationally bound...
遍及数亿光年的范围
up to hundreds of millions of light-years across.
宇宙是由组织的体系
The universe is organized hierarchically.
恒星构成了星系
Stars make up galaxies...
星系构成了星团
galaxies make up clusters...
星团构成了超星系团
clusters make up superclusters.
你可以打一个比方
You could draw an analogy...
星团就像是北美大陆
that a cluster might be the North American continent...
超星系团就像是北美大陆以及
and a supercluster might be the association of cities...on the North American continent...
欧洲大陆 亚洲大陆等等的城市协会
cities on the European continent...cities on the Asian continent, et cetera.
目前 星系间的最大超星系团的纪录保持者
The current record holder...for the largest supercluster of galaxies...
叫做夏普里超星系团
is called the Shapley Supercluster.
这个星系密集区有4亿光年长
This dense region of galaxies...is 400 million light-years long.
所以 即使坐上最快的星际飞船
So it would take the fastest interplanetary spacecraft...
也需要数万亿年才能穿越它
trillions ofyears to travel across it.
夏普里超星系团跨越多个星座
The Shapley Supercluster spans several constellations...
距离我们的银河系几近6.5亿光年
and is almost 650 million light-years...from our Milky Way galaxy.
我这里有一只小玩具船
l have here a small toy boat...
是玛丽皇后号的复制品
which is a replica of the Queen Mary...
其原型就在我身后
which you can see here behind me.
这个小玩具约比真的玛丽皇后号小4000倍
And this little toy is about 4,000 times smaller...than the real Queen Mary.
你就来想象一下
lfyou could just imagine...
我们居住的银河系就如这个小玩具
that our own Milky Way galaxy that we live in...is the same size as this toy boat...
而最大的超星系团之一
then one of the most massive superclusters...
就是我们知道的夏普里超星系团
that we know about, the Shapley Supercluster...
就如玛丽皇后号那般大
would be the same size as theQueen Mary.
因此 夏普里超星系团
So the Shapley Supercluster...
就会比我们的银河系大4000倍
would be about 4,000 times larger than our own Milky Way.
那是我们所知道的整个宇宙间最大的东西了
lt's one of the most massive things we know about...in the entire universe.
天文学家自1950年代起就知道了超星系团
Astronomers have known about superclusters...since the 1950s...
不过现在他们已经确定了它们的起源
but now they've determined their origin...
通过最近的宇宙微波背景测量
through recent measurements...of the cosmic microwave background...
那其实是大爆炸所留下的辐射
which is actual radiation left overfrom the Big Bang.
得到的结论是所有的超星系团
lt's been concluded that all superclusters...
包括夏普里超星系团
including the Shapley Supercluster...
都起源于130亿年前宇宙形成期间
originated during the formation of the universe...over 13 billion years ago.
在宇宙的演化和膨胀过程中
As the universe evolves and expands...
引力发挥了吸引的作用
gravity is an attractive force...
所以任何稍微致密的区域
so any region that has a little extra density there...
都会吸引越来越多的物质
attracts more matter and more matter.
夏普里作为星团
So, Shapley is a cluster...
总体上聚集了落入其中的许多小星系
that basically had the accumulation...of many other little galaxies falling into it...
那就是 它随着时间推移变得如此之大的原因所在
and that's how it's gotten so big over time.
难以置信的是 科学家认为夏普里超星系团
lncredibly, scientists think the Shapley Supercluster...
可能比它反映出来的还要大
may be even bigger than it appears.
事实上 我们可能只看到了夏普里超星系团
ln fact, we may only be seeing a small fraction...
真实内容的很小一部分
ofwhat's really contained within the Shapley Supercluster.
在广域红外探测器升空后
When the Wide-Field lnfrared Survey explorer launches...
我们应该看到10倍远
we should be able to see about10 times farther away...
希望我们能够看到夏普里超星系团的其余部分
and hopefully, we'll be able to see...the rest of the Shapley Supercluster...
以确定它是否比我们已经掌握的更加庞大
to see if it is even more massive...than what we already know about.
超星系团随着时间的推移会聚集在一起
Superclusters of galaxies will stay together over time...
因为它们被引力所约束
because they're gravitationally bound.
引力将它们牢牢控制
Gravity is holding them together.
因此 即使宇宙在膨胀
So, even though the universe is expanding...
随着时间的推移 这些超星系团也将聚拢在一起
over time those superclusters of galaxies will stay together...
它们始终保持着相互围绕
and they'll always keep orbiting each other.
我们人类同样生活在一个超星系团里
We humans also live in a supercluster complex...
但是 相对夏普里超星系团
but it's less than half the size...
个头小于其一半 质量只有其一成还不到
and about10 times less massive...than the Shapley Supercluster.
我们银河系归属于一个小星团
Our Milky Way is part of a small, little cluster...
叫做本星系
called the Local Group...
它又属于一个大星团
which is part of a larger cluster...
叫做室女座星团
called the Virgo Cluster...
好像是在它的郊外
sort of on the outskirts ofthat.
所以就像是你的家庭地址
So it's like your home address.
你居住在XX街 XX镇
You live on this street, in this town...
XX州 XX国
in this state, in this country.
同样 银河系也有自己归属的越来越大的社会
Similarly, the Milky Way...has its larger and larger associations...of which it's a part.
超星系团是太空里最拥挤的街区
Superclusters of galaxies...are the most crowded neighborhoods in space...
然而他们四周是同样大的区域
but they surround equally big regions...
那里几乎空无一物
where almost nothing exists.
这些空无一物的地方称为巨洞
These bare spots are called voids.
巨洞是星团的对立面
Voids are the opposite of clusters.
如果星团到处都是星系的话
lf clusters are where all the galaxies are...
那么巨洞就是到处都不存在星系
voids are where all the galaxies aren't.
你确实看到了这种泡沫
And you do see this kind off rothy, weblike structure...
星团与巨洞 巨洞与星团构成的网状结构
of clusters and voids and clusters and voids.
这就像是城市与乡村
So it's kind of like cities and countrysides...
乡村与城市
cities and countryside.
经确认宇宙间最大的巨洞依然是牧夫座
The largest confirmed void in the universe remains Bootes.
名字来自它所处的星座
Named after the constellation where it resides...
这个几近空白的空间
this near-empty space...
横跨2.5亿光年
is a whopping 250 million light-years across.
那相当于2500个银河系横贯其中
That's equal to 2,500 Milky Way galaxies...placed side by side.
从任何方向观察宇宙
Look out into the cosmos in any direction...
你都会看到点什么
and you'll see something.
会看到东西 看到星系
You'll see stuff, you'll see galaxies...
气体 尘埃 会发现暗物质
you'll see gas, dust, you'll detect dark matter.
你所见之处 都有东西
Everywhere you look, there's something.
然而这个巨洞里却什么都没有
Yet here's this giant hole with nothing in it.
牧夫巨洞 发现于1981年
The Bootes Void, which was discovered in 1981...
几乎是星系的盲区
is almost completely devoid of galaxies.
搜寻更大巨洞的新方法有可能
A newway to search for even largervoids may be possible...
通过精确测量宇宙微波背景辐射的温度来实现
by precise measurements of the temperatures...of the cosmic microwave background radiation.
这个辐射的细微冷点
Subtle cold spots in this radiation...
可以定位远距离巨洞的方向
could locate the directions of large distant voids.
它们形成的故事
The story of theirformation...
与超星系团的形成刚好相反
is basically the reverse of how superclusters form.
巨洞必定始于大爆炸的那一刻
The voids must have started out...in the first microsecond of the Big Bang...
形成于密度略低一点的区域里
as slightly low-density regions.
然而 随着时间的推移 它们的密度越来越小
But with time, they became less and less dense.
所有的物质流失成了片状和丝状
All of the matter flowed away into the sheets and filaments...
离开了物质越来越稀少的巨洞
leaving the voids emptier and emptier of matter...
直至今日 几乎一片空白
until today, there is almost nothing...
但是某些巨洞里还有一些矮星系
but a few little dwarf galaxies in some of these voids.
巨洞和超星系团就是那些大家伙
Voids and superclusters are just some of the big things...
被收纳在更大的结构里
contained in the even larger structure...
那就是宇宙网络
called the cosmic web.
然而网络里还有其它的大家伙
But the web also holds other immense objects...
包括巨泡
including colossal bubbles...
里头可能隐藏着丢失的星系形成的线索
that might hold missing clues to the formation of galaxies.
宇宙充满了巨大的东西
The universe is packed with monstrous things.
研究人员最近发现了巨大的气体云
Researchers have recently discovered...giant clouds of gas...
类似于恐怖电影里的东西
that resemble something out of a horror movie.
这些神秘的对象被称为莱曼α云团
These mysterious objects are called Lyman-Alpha blobs.
我个人最喜欢的宇宙间的大哥大
My personal favorite biggest objects in the universe...
就是莱曼α云团
are the Lyman-Alpha blobs...
一个完全意想不到的现象
an unpredicted, unexpected phenomenon...
在那里 你可以捕捉到形成与消亡第一时间的星系
where you're catching a galaxy in the first phases...of its formation and collapse.
莱曼α云团
A Lyman-Alpha blob...
非常像这个不断膨胀的肥皂泡
is very much like this expanding soap bubble...
只不过 在这个肥皂泡案例里
except, in the case of the soap bubble...
里头充满的是空气
it's the airwhich is making it fill up.
莱曼α云团因热而膨胀
A Lyman-Alpha blob is expanding because of heat.
大量的能量注入气体 使其加热
A lot of energy has been injected into this gas...to make it heat up.
在你将能量注入气体后
And when you put all that energy into a gas...
必然会导致鼓起 膨胀
it inevitably tends to puff up and expand...
酷似膨胀的泡沫
exactly like an expanding bubble.
对于莱曼α云团
ln the case of a Lyman-Alpha blob,
其膨胀源自热
it's being puffed up by heat...
或许 还有新形成的恒星发出的紫外线辐射
and maybe also by the ultraviolet radiation...from newly formed stars.
已知最大的莱曼α云团
The largest known Lyman-Alpha blob...
是巨大的阿米巴状的结构
is a colossal, amoeba-shaped structure...
就像是个巨大的绿水母
that resembles a giant greenjellyfish.
它宽达2亿光年
lt's 200 million light-years wide...
位于宝瓶座里
and is located in the constellation Aquarius.
我们观察那个莱曼α云团
When we're looking at the Lyman-Alpha blob...
会看到气体好像环绕着初生的恒星和星系扩散
we're seeing gas that sort of spread...amongst these very first stars and galaxies.
好像没有固定的形状
lt's kind of an amorphous shape...
里头约有30个小云团
of about 30 separate little blobs inside of it.
其体积非常庞大
lt's very large and very massive.
整个结构约是我们银河系的30倍
The whole structure is about 3,000 times the size...of our own Milky Way galaxy.
夏威夷的凯克和斯巴鲁望远镜
The Keck and Subaru telescopes in Hawaii...
装有特殊的滤镜
contain special filters...
能够看到这个远方的云团
that are able to see this faraway blob...
伸展出弯曲的触须
which spreads out along curvy tentacles.
科学家估计最大的莱曼α云团
Scientists estimate that the largest Lyman-Alpha blob...
形成于120亿年前
was formed about 12 billion years ago...
接近大爆炸后20亿年
almost two billion years after the Big Bang.
我们用来观察气体的技术
The observational technique we use to see that gas...
针对非常特殊的光色 就是所谓的莱曼α光线
refers to a very specific color of light, emission of light...that's called Lyman-Alpha.
你听到莱曼α云团
So you hear a phrase Lyman-Alpha blob...
那是因为你要是在对天空成像时
because ifyou take an image of the sky...
用上了一个透镜 只能让莱曼α通过
through a filter that gives you only that Lyman-Alpha light...
一种非常特殊的光波
that very special wavelength of light...
就可以看到空中小小的云团
you'll see a little blob on the sky.
莱曼α云团或许就是我们今天所见的星系团的前身
Lyman-Alpha blobs are perhaps precursors...to the galaxy clusters we see today.
这些巨泡里面可能存在着茧
Within these gigantic bubbles may exist cocoons...
有朝一日会孵化出新的星系
that will one day spawn new galaxies.
莱曼α云团可能是星系诞生的演化的
The Lyman-Alpha blobs are probably...
一个相对特殊的短暂阶段
a fairly special short-lived phase...in the evolution to creating a galaxy.
我预计其中大部分
l would expect that most of them...
在未来1亿年里塌缩形成新的星系
are going to collapse and form young galaxies...
或者说在它们的生命中
in the next100 million years or so of their lives...
这是个特殊的阶段
so it's a special phase...
也就是星系开始自我振奋起来了
just when a galaxy is beginning to pull itself together.
搜索宇宙间的莱曼α云团
The search in the universe for Lyman-Alpha blobs...
才刚刚起步
isjust beginning.
无疑我们将会发现更多的
We'll undoubtedly find many more of them...
甚至有可能在将来发现更大的云团
and even perhaps some larger ones in the future.
敬请关注
Stay tuned.
莱曼α云团可能掌握着某些星系形成的答案
Lyman-Alpha blobs may hold the answers...to the formation of individual galaxies...
那些是引力约束系统
which are gravitationally bound systems...
包括了恒星 气体 尘埃以及暗物质
containing stars, gas, dust, and dark matter.
在有形的宇宙间至少存在着1000亿个星系
At least100 billion single galaxies exist...in the observable universe.
其大小从1万光年到数百万光年不等
They range in size...from ten thousand to millions of light-years across.
星系 这些巨大的星体集合体
Galaxies, these titanic collections of stars...
我认为它们就像是城市
l think of them as cities...
我就出生在其中的一座城市里
having been born in one myself...
不光星系 实际上还有城市
not only a galaxy, but also an actual city...
纽约天生就是人们趋之若鹜的地方
a native of New Yorkwhere everyone is crowded together.
星系好像是宇宙间物质在自我管理
Galaxies are sort of how matter has organized itself...in the universe.
在宇宙间最大的星系的竞争中
ln the competition for largest single galaxy in the universe...
判断赢家是个挑战
sizing up a winner is challenging.
确定最大星系的问题
The problem in saying what's the largest galaxy...
在于判定它们的边界
is in deciding where they end.
星系并没有清晰的边界
Galaxy does not have a sharp edge.
随着你往外走 只会变得越来越稀薄
ltjust gets thinner and thinner...as you go further out.
完全可以这么说
lt's exactly analogous to saying...
哪里才是大都会的尽头呢？
where is the end of a very large metropolitan area?
哪里才是洛杉矶的尽头呢？
Where is the end of Los Angeles?
你可以走出50英里
You can go out 50 miles...
你还会发现密度很高的郊区
and you'll still find a fairly high density of suburbs.
银河系这样的大星系的郊外
The suburbs of a big galaxy like the Milky Way...
延展得非常广阔 超过了10万光年
extend out very, very far, more than 100,000 light-years.
在一个大星系里 郊区会延展出数十万光年
And with a giant galaxy, those suburbs extend out...hundreds of thousands of light-years.
由于科学家无法明确谁是赢家
Since scientists can't determine a clearwinner...
有几个星系分享了最大的头衔
several galaxies share the title as biggest.
它们叫做星团扩散星系 简称CD星系
They're called cluster-diffused or CD galaxies...
它们位于簇拥的星系团的中央
and they sit in the centers of rich clusters of galaxies.
如果你认为宇宙网络就像是三维的蜘蛛网的话
lfyou think about the cosmic web as being...sort of like a three-dimensional spiderweb...
那么 蛰伏在网中央的蜘蛛
well, then, the spiders lurking in the middle of the web...
就是这些可怕的CD星系 姑且这么称呼它们
are these monstrous CD galaxies, as we call them.
这些星系的质量
These galaxies can have masses...
某些情况下 会是我们银河系的10到20倍
that are in some cases maybe 10 times or 20 times...the mass of our own Milky Way.
这些CD星系是宇宙间最大的星系
These CD galaxies...are the largest galaxies in the universe.
比如 IC-1101位于阿贝尔-2029星系团的中央
For example, lC-1101 sits in the center...of a galaxy cluster called Abell-2029...
跨越了600万光年
and it's six million light-years across.
我们的银河系相对就只有10万光年宽
Compare that to our own Milky Way...that's100,000 light-years across.
它真是个大星系
lt's a really big galaxy.
其个头是银河系的60倍
lt's 60 times the size of our Milky Way.
CD星系都是椭圆形
CD galaxies are elliptically shaped...
完全不同于我们银河系这样的圆盘结构
as opposed to a disc structure like our Milky Way.
这是因为它们已经达到了那样的规模
This is because they've achieved their size...
即通过星系的兼并吸纳了其它的星系
by bulking up on other galaxies...through galaxy mergers.
你可能听说过"星系吞食"
You may have heard the phrase "galaxy cannibalism"...
也就是星系吃星系
where one galaxy eats another.
那种情形一直在星系团里发生
That goes on all the time in clusters of galaxies.
所以 通常在巨大星团的中央
And so, sitting usually down at the very center...
你都能够发现一个大星系
of a massive cluster, you'll find one big galaxy.
这些CD星系个头巨大
These CD galaxies have so much mass...
不管在哪 都是一头800磅的大猩猩
that they are the 800-pound gorilla...wherever they are.
你可以看到有小星系围绕着它们
You see little galaxies maybe orbiting around them...
不过基本上 它会吞下周围的一切
but, basically, it's eaten up everything nearby.
最大的星系可能会有600到2000万光年宽
The largest galaxies may be...six to 20 million light-years across.
不过 还有比这更大的东西
However, there are other objects even larger.
它们叫做射电瓣
They're called radio lobes.
从星系的两侧伸出
Stretching out from both sides of the galaxy...
这些巨大的结构
these immense structures...
实际上是喷出的带电粒子流
are actually hurling jets of charged particles...
喷出的无线电波
that emit radio waves.
我们现在是在车身工厂
So we're here in this auto body shop...
我要用这两把喷枪来模拟无线电射流
where l'm gonna use these two torches...to simulate radiojets...
从积吸盘的两侧喷出
coming out of opposite sides of an accretion disc...
围绕着超级黑洞旋转
swirling around a supermassive black hole.
肉眼观察
So in the visible...
你可以看到喷枪喷出的蓝色火焰
you see a small blue flame coming off of the torch.
然而在红外线里
But in the infrared...
你可以看到喷枪发出的热量
you can see that the heat from the torch...
扩展得更远
extends much, much further out.
同样 无线电射流
Similarly with the radiojets...
你肉眼所见是完全不同于
what you see in the optical is actually quite different...
你在无线电波里所见到的
from what you see in radio waves.
典型的射电瓣可能会有16万光年
A typical lobe might be 160,000 light-years...
伸出在星系的两侧
as the lobe spreads out on both sides of the galaxy.
那几乎是银河系圆盘的两倍
That's about twice the size of the Milky Way galaxy's disc.
天文学家认为 射电瓣的能量来自
Astronomers think radio lobes are powered...
类星体中的超大质量黑洞
by supermassive black holes located in quasars.
它们是最活跃星系的发光中心
These are the luminous centers of most active galaxies.
无线电喷射来自大黑洞
Thejets of radio energy...that come from a giant black hole...
产生了这些巨大的射电瓣
and make these enormous radio lobe structures...
与类星体关系密切
are very closely related to quasars.
事实上 某下情况下 你可以在
ln fact, in some cases, you can see a low-power quasar...
星系中心看到低能量的类星体
in the center of the galaxy...
它被这些巨大的射电瓣中的一侧所包围
and then it's surrounded by these giant lobes...to either side.
它们在这些高能电流作用下喷出
They have been blasted out...by very high-energy jets of electrons...
速度基本上接近于光速
that are basically moving at almost the speed of light.
它们喷出 有可能
And they are blasted out, probably...
是从旋转的黑洞的南北两极喷出
from the north and south poles of the spinning black hole.
射电瓣依赖掉进黑洞里的物质
The radio lobes depend on matter going down the black hole.
随着物质掉进黑洞
As matter goes down the black hole...
其中的一些会加速进入这些射电瓣
some of it gets accelerated up into these lobes.
因此射电瓣的大小牵涉到
So the size of the lobes has something to do...
黑洞实际掉进了多少物质的过程
with the history of how much matter...the black hole has actually fed on.
所以随着时间的推移 它们会改变大小的
And so over time, they'll change size.
射电望远镜纵览宇宙
Radio telescopes have surveyed the universe...
已经确定了最大的射电瓣
and determined the largest known radio lobe.
无可争辩的纪录保持者
The undeniable record holder...
位于3C236星系内
is located in the galaxy named 3C236...
就是在小狮星座内
which is in the constellation Leo Minor.
其喷射延展出4000万光年
ltsjets span 40 million light-years across.
科学家纳闷的是
Scientists don't understand...
为何某些活跃的星系会形成这些喷射
why some active galaxies form thesejets...
而其它星系就不行呢 不过有一点是肯定的
and others don't, but one thing is certain...
射电瓣不会永远存在
radio lobes will not last forever...
或许 就只能存在几百万年
perhaps for only a few million years.
所以就像这喷枪最终耗尽了燃气
So, just as this torch will eventually run out of gas...
自己熄火了一样
and shut itself off...
射电星系发出的射流最终也将熄灭
thejets from a radio galaxy will eventually die as well.
一旦黑洞耗尽其周围的物质
When the black hole has consumed...all of the material in its immediate vicinity...
就会什么都不会留给积吸盘
there'll be nothing left of the accretion disc...
沿着磁力线喷出
to get shot out along the magnetic field lines...
此时喷射将告终结
and thejet will die.
如果黑洞就是这些巨大的射电瓣的始作俑者
lf black holes are the producers...of these gigantic radio lobes...
那么宇宙间最大的黑洞又在哪里呢？
then what is the largest black hole in the universe?
目前科学家正在投注赢家
Scientists are currently placing bets on the winner.
提及宇宙间的大哥大
When it comes to the biggest things in the universe...
某些黑洞获得了记录本上的一席之地
some black holes earn a place in the record books.
黑洞是太空中的一个区域
A black hole is a region of space...
在那里 引力超大
where the pull of gravity is so immense...
任何东西都难逃其魔爪 光也不例外
that nothing can escape it, not even light.
无数黑怪兽遍布宇宙
There are billions upon billions of these black monsters...prowling the universe.
它们可以归类为两种规模
They come in two size categories.
其中多数属于恒星级黑洞
Most of them are the stellar mass black holes...
质量约是太阳的5到100倍
which are about five to 100 times...the mass of our sun.
然后是超大质量黑洞
And then there are supermassive black holes...
质量是太阳的百万到数十亿倍
that are millions to billions of times the mass of the sun.
我们看到的超大质量黑洞
We have the supermassive black holes...
就是我们在每个星系中心所见到的那种
the kind that we seem to be finding...in the centers of every galaxy...
是我们有据可查的
where we've had the resources to look.
浩劫就会降临你的头上
Havoc is wrought upon your environment...
只要你是一颗围绕着星系中央的
if you're a star orbiting...
一个超大质量黑洞运转的恒星
close to one of these supermassive black holes...in the centers of these galaxies.
黑洞本质上并非大的区域
Black holes are not physically large regions...
不过要是以质量来衡量
but when measuring their mass...
它们就会成为星系间重量级的最大竞争者
they become top competitors...in the galactic heavyweight division.
我们银河系中央
The center of our Milky Way...
我们知道那里的黑洞
we know that there's a black hole...
可能是我们太阳质量的300万倍
that's about maybe three million times...the mass of our own sun.
然而 由于黑洞的密度非常之大
And yet, because black holes are so incredibly dense...
以至于黑洞的实际尺寸还是相当的小
the actual size of the black hole...is still fairly small...
然而却有着异常强大的引力
but incredibly, incredibly powerful gravitationally.
顾名思义 这些黑怪兽
As their name suggests, these black beasts...
基本上漆黑一团
are essentially black...
原因就在于光都逃脱不了
because no light can escape them.
所以唯一能观察到它
So one can only be observed...
就是在其引力影响太空中的其它东西时
when its gravity affects something else in space...
诸如路过的恒星
such as a passing star...
或者在它吞食周围的物质时
orwhen it's gorging on matter around it.
那么谁是当今黑洞的冠军呢？
So what is the reigning black hole champion?
目前最大黑洞的记录保持者
The current record holder for the largest black hole...
看来就在极亮的类星体里
appears to be in the incredibly luminous quasar...
其名字平淡无奇 HS1946+7658
which has the prosaic-sounding name HS1946+7658.
为何我会说它就是最大的黑洞呢？
Why do l say it's the largest black hole?
因为我们知道它是
Because we know it is...
目前为止所发现的宇宙间最亮的类星体
the most luminous quasar in the universe...that's been found so far.
黑洞将其牢牢掌握
The black hole that's holding it together...
其产生的能量需要太阳质量的约100亿倍
that's producing the energy...needs to be about 10 billion times...the mass of the sun.
相当于黑洞要比我们整个太阳系还大
That corresponds to a black hole...which is larger than our entire solar system.
事实上 它在那里提醒着我们
ln fact, it'sjust out there to remind us how bizarre...
一个看似简单的引力居然会有这么怪异
a seemingly simple force like gravity can actually be.
最大的超大质量黑洞
The largest supermassive black hole...
在星系中央掌控大权
wields power in the center of a galaxy...
不过在宇宙间还有其它的大发光体
but there are other big luminous objects...in the universe.
事实上 我们环顾四周 似乎还存在着某些东西
ln fact, there are some that seem to exist...everywhere we look.
当我们扫视夜空时
When we glance into the nighttime sky...
看到星星 闪烁着星光
we see stars, twinkling dots of light...
那实际上是发光的等离子球
that are actually luminous balls of plasma.
尽管从地球上看 它们很小
Although they may seem small from Earth...
然而星星有各种各样的个头
stars come in a variety of sizes...
从红矮星 我们太阳质量的1/12
from red dwarfs...which are about1/12 the mass of our sun...
到蓝白超级巨星
to blue-white super giants...
可以达到太阳质量的150倍
that can get as big as 150 solar masses.
我们银河系里有1亿颗恒星
Our Milky Way holds 100 billion stars...
包括我们的太阳
including our sun...
它是我们地球质量的30万倍
which is over 300,000 times the mass of planet Earth.
这个宇宙灯塔
And this cosmic beacon...
是我们太阳系里的发电站
is a literal powerhouse in our solar system.
这座天然气发电厂
This natural gas power plant...
发出300兆瓦的电力
produces about 300 megawatts of power.
告诉你 足以满足几十万户家庭
You know, that's enough to power...a few hundred thousand homes.
但是那只是我们太阳能量输出的一丁点
But that's only a tiny fraction of our sun's energy output.
太阳能约是这座电站发电量的200亿亿倍
The sun's power is about two billion, billion times...the amount of this plant.
所以 即使距离遥远
So even in spite of its distance...
太阳还是能够温暖我们整个地球
the sun is able to warm our entire planet.
即便如此 太阳绝对不是最大
Even so, our sun isn't the largest...
或最强大的恒星
or the most powerful star by a long shot.
最强大的恒星要比太阳强大上百万倍
The most powerful stars...are about a million times as powerful as the sun.
如果你想拿胡佛大坝与之相比
So ifyou wanted to compare that with the Hoover Dam...
就需要地球上每人30万亿个胡佛大坝
you would need 30 million, million...Hoover Dams per person on the planet...
才能产生如此多的能量
to generate that much power.
人类尺度简直无法想象这样的能量输出
There's really no human scale to imagine this power output.
能产生这种能量的最大最强的恒星
The largest and most powerful stars...that produce this kind of energy...
叫做红巨星
are called red hyper giants.
那一类恒星甚至比超级巨星还大
That's a class of stars...that's even larger than super giant stars.
恒星的典型代表如我们的太阳
So typically, stars like our sun...
将氢聚合成氦产生能量
are fusing hydrogen into helium to make their energy.
而红巨星
But hyper giant stars...
已经耗尽了核心的氢
have already exhausted all the hydrogen in their core...
它们是在将核心外围的氢聚合成氦
and they're fusing hydrogen into helium...in the out skirts around the core...
使得它们温度极高 活力四射
and that makes them extremely hot and energetic...
整个能量造成了星体膨胀
and all that energy causes the star to swell up...
所以星体终结于极大的表面积
and so the star ends up with a very large surface area...
超过了地球的轨道甚至更大
surface areas of the size of the Earth's orbit...or even bigger.
在红巨星的庞大领域里
Within the hefty field of red hyper giants...
大犬座VY
VY Canis Majoris...
貌似具有最大的直径
appears to have the largest diameter.
其直径是太阳的2000倍
lt's 2,000 times wider than our sun...
因此 用世界上最快的赛车
and consequently, it would take the world's fastest race car...
跑上一圈需要2600年才行
2,600 years to circle it once.
这个星际冠军坐落在距离地球5000光年的地方
This stellar champ lives about 5,000 light-years from Earth...
在大犬座里
in the constellation Canis Majoris.
如果你用大犬座VY来取代太阳
lfyou replace the sun with VY Canis Majoris...
如果你将这颗巨星放在太阳的位置
ifyou put this hyper giant star where the sun is...
其半径就已经越过了土星的轨道
its radius would extend out past Saturn's orbit.
那是太阳与地球距离的9倍
lt would be about nine times as far from the sun...as the Earth is...
所以说这是个直径比太阳大得多的恒星
so this is a much broader in diameter star...than our sun is.
天文学家测定如此大的恒星
Astronomers determine the radius of such a large star...
是通过观察它的温度
by looking at its temperature.
我们测量星球表面的温度
We use measurements...of the temperature of the star's surface...
可以从其颜色来得到
which we can get from the color of the star...
于是我们也会测量其总能量输出
and then we will also measure the total power output...
即星体的亮度
or luminosity of the star.
综合起来 我们可以测定
And by combining those, we can determine...
星体的总表面积
what its total surface area is of the star...
并据此 得到它的直径
and from that, we get its diameter.
现在 假设
Now, that assumes...
你可以非常理想地测量其亮度
that you can measure its luminosity fairly well...
你就可以根据其颜色来知道其温度什么的了
and that you know something about its temperature...from its color.
多数时间
Most of the time...
它们只是表现出一个光点
they just simply appear as pinpoints of light...
不可能实际解决问题
and it's impossible to actually resolve it.
然而 现在有了新的仪器
Although there are new instruments now...
叫做干涉仪
called interferometers...
它具有解决问题的能力
which are capable of resolving...
即使是星星这样的光点
even very tiny point sources, like stars.
某些案例中
And in some cases...
已经有了恒星直径的直接测量了
there have been direct measurements...of stellar diameters.
大犬座VY不会是记录的永远保持者
VY Canis Majoris will not be a title holderforever.
这个红巨星正在失去质量
The red hyper giant is losing mass...
其速度几乎是每年30个地球的质量甚至更多
at the rate of almost 30 Earth masses or more peryear.
宇宙间最大的恒星
The largest stars in the universe...
如大犬座VY
like VY Canis Majoris...
实际上是垂死的恒星
are actually dying stars...
随着恒星开始死亡时
that as stars begin to die...
燃烧核燃料极不稳定
they burn their nuclearfuel much less stably.
它们的熄灭指日可待
They puff out over time.
大犬座VY或许只有几百万岁
VY Canis Majoris is probably only a few million years old.
如此个头的恒星寿命不会很长
Stars that are as massive as it is don't live very long.
它们耗用自己燃料的速度惊人
They use theirfuel up at prodigious rates...
于是它们会膨胀进入巨星状态
then they swell up into this hyper giant state...
只生存了几十万年
and only live there...for a few hundred thousand years...
时间很短
a very short time scale...
然后它们就会爆发
and then they will explode.
大犬座VY的直径可能最大
VY Canis Majoris might have the largest diameter...
不过要论拥有最大质量的话
but when it comes to possessing the most mass...
其它恒星则当仁不让了
there's another star that tips the scale.
在恒星的庞大世界里
ln the wide world of stars...
有许多竞争者
there are many contenders...
在竞争宇宙间的第一把交椅
vying for the title as the largest in the universe.
然而提到恒星
But when it comes to stars...
大意味着两种情况
big can mean two different things.
你说起最大的恒星
When you talk about the biggest star...
可以指两者之一
you can mean one of two things.
你可以说是最大的直径
You can either mean the star that has the largest diameter...
也可以说是最大的质量
oryou might mean what its mass is.
质量是指衡量有多少物质
The mass is a measure of how much stuffyou have.
就好像你站在磅秤上称体重
lt's sort of like yourweight when you step on a scale...
你身体中究竟有多少物质
how much matter your body is made of.
据一些天文学家称
According to some astronomers...
最重的恒星就在银河系里
the most massive star is located...in our Milky Way galaxy.
它是一个叫做Al双星系统的组成部分
lts part of a binary star system known as A1...
那实际上是两颗星
which is actually two stars...
相互围绕 每四天运转一次
that orbit each other once every four days.
我们发现其中的一颗恒星
We find there that one of the stars...
呈现出其质量达到了太阳的115倍
appears to have a mass...of about 115 times the mass of the sun...
另一颗也非常庞大
and the other star is also enormous...
约是太阳质量的84倍
about 84 times the mass of the sun.
因而这两颗孪生恒星
So both stars in this binary...
属于我们所测量过的最重的恒星
are among the most massive stars that we have ever measured.
在这个星团里会有质量比Al组合更大的恒星
There may be more massive stars...than the combination in A1 in this star cluster...
不过对于质量最大的
but that's the most massive...
我们已经能够直接测量了
that we've been able to measure directly.
这些大块头恒星养尊处优 但人生苦短
These massive stars will live full, but short lives.
大质量恒星光彩夺目
Massive stars are hugely luminous.
有时会在它们街坊的群星中一枝独秀
Sometimes they can outshine...millions of stars in their neighborhood...
代价是它们消耗的燃料快于其它人
but at a cost. The cost is they will run out offuel...faster than everybody else...
并且寿终正寝时非常悲壮
and when they die, they die spectacularly.
它们整体爆发 撒向星系
They explode their guts...and scatter it across the galaxy.
所以说高质量星生的生活成本
So the cost of living a high-mass life...
闪亮的星生
a high-luminous life...
快车道上的生活成本
the cost of living in the fast lane...
就是你在生命尽头的爆发
is that you explode at the end ofyour life.
璀璨明星可能会燃烧更快 死得更早
A bright star may burn out faster and die sooner...
但是 同时
but at the same time...
那些明星也在炮制生命所必需的元素
those hot stars are cooking up elements...that are essential for life.
所以要是没有巨星 也就没有我们
So without really massive stars, we wouldn't be here...
因为你就会没有血液里的铁
because you wouldn't get the iron in my blood...
骨骼里的钙
and the calcium in my bones.
所有这些只能形成于巨星之中
All ofthose things are formed only in the most massive stars.
我们人类需要从巨星中获得必要的元素
We humans need essential elements from massive stars...
不多我们也需要有坚实地表的行星来站稳脚跟
but we also need a planet with a firm surface to stand on.
行星分为两个规模等级
Planets come in two size groups...
大的气体巨星如木星
large gas giants like Jupiter...
小的岩质类地行星如地球
and small rocky terrestrials such as Earth.
在我们太阳系里
ln our own solar system...
木星是最大的行星
Jupiter is the largest planet...
而地球则排名第五
while Earth trails in fifth place.
然而 尽管木星在我们星系的排名中至高无上
Yet, even though Jupiter reigns supreme...in our galactic zip code...
但是并不是宇宙间最大的行星
it's not the biggest planet in the universe.
已知半径最大的行星是TRES4
The largest planet with a well-known radius...is called TRES4.
其名字来自跨大西洋系外行星搜索网
lt's named after...the Trans-Atlantic Exoplanet Survey...
是2006年在武仙座里发现的
that discovered it in the constellation Hercules...in 2006.
TRES4的个头非常之大
TRES4 is unusually large for its mass.
眼下我们可以直接测量其半径
We can actually directly measure its radius...
这个特殊的行星有着极大的半径
and this particular planet has an unusually large radius.
它比木星大出七成
lt's about 70 percent bigger than Jupiter...
可是质量却只有木星的八成
yet it has only about 80 percent of Jupiter"s mass.
大约就是软木甚至奶油那样的密度
That's about the same density as cork or even whipped cream.
你看地球
lfyou look at Earth...
那是颗岩石行星 非常致密
it's a rocky planet, very dense...
哪怕木星那样的气体巨星
and then even the gas giant planets like Jupiter...
压缩气体和水
are compressed gas and water
以及其它化学物质也是紧紧地压缩的
and other chemicals very tightly compressed.
这家伙 TRES4 简直就像棉花糖
This thing, TRES4, is like a marshmallow.
虽然 TRES4 出彩在个头上
Although TRES4 is light for its size...
约比地球大上18倍
it's about18 times larger than Earth.
但是 科学家还是不能确定TRES4为何会如此之大
Scientist aren't exactly sure how TRES4 got so large.
一种理论认为这颗行星太靠近其母星了
One theory is that the planet's extremely close distance...
烧烤着大气中的化学物质
to its parent star...
is cooking up a lot of chemicals in its atmosphere...
获取热量 极像温室气体
which is trapping heat much like greenhouse gases.
这颗特殊的行星
This particular planet...
距离其母星只有日地距离的5%
is only about five percent of the Earth's sun distance...from its parent star...
所以说它靠得太近了
so it's very, very close.
事实上 它距离近到
ln fact, it's so close...
围绕母星运转一周才三天半
it orbits its star every three and a half days.
所以你可以想象会有多热
So you can imagine how hot...
阳光有多厉害
and howjust blasted with sunlight...
情况并定是这样的
this thing must be.
因为它无法冷却 所以也就无法收缩
Because the planet can't cool off, it can't shrink.
因为只要它温度非常高
Because when it's very hot...
气体温度非常高 就会膨胀
when gases are very hot, they expand...
所以这就有可能导致
so this might be contributing...
一直让这颗行星的半径保持很大
to keeping the radius of this planet so very large.
TRES4可能是颗趾高气扬的行星
TRES4 may be a puffed-up planet...
不过要说维持生命
but when it comes to sustaining life...
大行星可不是首选之地了
bigger planets don't offer prime real estate.
这些大行星其实就是气体
These giant planets really arejust gas.
它们根本就没有坚实的结构
There's no solid structure to them at all.
没有立足之地
There's nowhere to stand on them.
所以极不可能发现生命
So it's not a very likely place to find life...
因为 生命会在大气中吹得四处游荡
'cause life would have to continually be blown around...in the atmosphere...
很难在那里进化
and that's a hard thing to evolve from.
这颗行星不是一个宜居之地
This planet would not be a very habitable place...
因为它太靠近母星了
because it's so close to its parent star.
它饱受母星辐射的煎熬
lt's getting blasted with radiation from its sun...
所以 那是个非常热的讨厌之地
so it would be a very hot and unpleasant place to be...
至少对人类是这样
at least for humans.
TRES4 是目前已知半径最大的行星
TRES4 currently has the largest known radius.
然而 这颗行星不久就将被挤掉首席地位
However, the planet could be bumped out offirst place...in the nearfuture.
科学家正在寻找新的行星
Scientists are finding new planets...
基本上每天都在乐此不疲
basically every day almost at this point.
因此 我们极有可能会发现另一颗行星
So it's quite possible that we will find another one...
甚至会比这颗特殊的行星更大
that's even bigger than this particular planet any time.
除了行星之外
ln addition to planets...
科学家也一直在搜寻新的小行星
scientists are also discovering new asteroids all the time.
那是些不会成为行星的岩石体
These are rocky bodies that didn't become planets...
最大的一颗可能就在我们星系里
and the largest one may exist in our galactic neighborhood.
在我们太阳系里
ln our own solar system...
无数剩余的石头
billions upon billions of leftover rocks...
成不了行星
that didn't become planets...
藏身于小行星带
take refuge in the asteroid belt.
有些小如尘埃粒
Some are as small as grains of dust...
其它则大如国土
and others are the size of nations.
谷神星是首个发现的小行星
Ceres was the first asteroid ever discovered...
它迄今保持着最大的小行星头衔
and it remains the largest known asteroid to date.
取名来自罗马耕种收获女神
Named after the Roman goddess of plants and harvest...
谷神星的直径约600英里
Ceres is about 600 miles in diameter...
所以它几乎和加州一样大
so it's almost as large as the state of California.
谷神星很大
Ceres is so big...
它占了小行星带质量总和的25%
that it contains 25 percent of all of the mass...in the asteroid belt.
谷神星很大 要是你将
Ceres is so big that if you took...
小行星带里的其它所有小行星粘在一起
all the other asteroids in the asteroid belt...and glued them all together...
它们也才比谷神星大上2到3倍
they'd only be about two or three times bigger than Ceres.
谷神星的个头将它有别于
Ceres' size sets it apart...
小行星带里其它石头
from the rest of the rocks in the asteroid belt.
可以让阿波罗登月车以时速8英里
lt would take the Apollo lunar rover10 days...
围绕这颗小行星跑上10天
to drive around the asteroid at eight miles per hour.
然而 除了其个头外
But in addition to its size...
其它鲜明的特征就是其圆圆的外形了
its other distinct feature is its round shape.
我们看到这些爱达荷土豆
We have all these ldaho potatoes...
在太阳系里的小行星带里转悠
orbiting in the asteroid belt of the solar system...
其中多数是坑坑洼洼的石头
most ofwhich are craggy chunks of rock.
谷神星很大 质量很大
Ceres is large enough, massive enough...
足以让其引力克服石头本身的力量了
that its gravity has overcome...the strength of the rocks that contain it.
到了此时 外形就变成了球形
And any time that happens, the shape becomes a sphere.
由于它的球形 谷神星现在拥有了双重头衔
Because of its round shape, Ceres now holds a dual title.
目前对于矮行星的定义
The current definition of a dwarf planet...
就是物体本质上质量足够大
is something that in fact is massive enough...
自身具有足够的引力
and has enough self gravity...
将自己变成球形
to form itself into a round shape.
事实上 由于谷神星是个球形
And, in fact, since Ceres is round...
我们也称其为
we also call it...
除了是颗小行星外
in addition to being an asteroid...
还是颗矮行星
a dwarf planet.
我们现在对谷神星的成分略知一二
We know only a little bit...about the composition of Ceres right now.
我们知道其成分主要是岩石
We know that it's made primarily of rock...
不过也有可能有冰
but it may also have water ice...
事实上 里面还可能会有粘土
and in fact, it could have clay inside it as well.
曙光计划其实就是去谷神星
The Dawn Mission is actually gonna go to Ceres...
进入它的轨道
and enter into orbit around it...
会带着全套设备去靠近它
and they'll bring a whole suite of instruments to bear on it...
所以我们会了解很多
so we should learn a lot more...
这个太阳系里非常大的小行星
about the composition of this unusually large asteroid...in our own solar system.
谷神星可能是我们太阳系里最大的小行星
Ceres may be the largest asteroid in our solar system...
但是大宇宙还在外头
but it's a big universe out there.
很有可能随着我们探索我们以外的太阳系
lt's quite possible that as we go on...to exploring other solar systems outside of our own...
我们会有朝一日
that we may in fact someday...
发现比谷神星更大的小行星
find an asteroid larger than Ceres.
我们太阳系里存在着一些超大天体
Our solar system contains some oversized objects.
最大的行星 木星
The largest planet, Jupiter...
有着最大的卫星 木卫三
has the biggest moon, named Ganymede.
火星其实有着最大的火山
Planet Mars actually contains the largest volcano...
叫做奥林匹斯山
called Olympus Mons.
它高达17英里
lt's 17 miles tall...
它比我们地球上最高的火山高出三倍
which makes it about three times taller...than the biggest volcano we have on Earth.
它高到你站在奥林匹斯山脚
lt's so tall...that ifyou stood at the base of Olympus Mons...
居然看不到山顶
you wouldn't be able to see the top...
那是因为火星本身的曲率
due to the curvature of Mars itself.
所以在我们太阳系里 大哥大
So in our own solar system, the biggest things...
肯定属于对宇宙形成强大影响的东西
definitely have had a powerful shaping effect on the universe.
有人可能会猜测非太阳莫属了
One might guess that the sun would take top honors...
它是我们宇宙都市中最大的物体
as the largest thing in our cosmic suburb.
它是木星质量的1000倍
lt's a thousand times more massive than Jupiter.
然而还有比这更大的东西了吗？
But is there something bigger?
与我们太阳系有关的最大的对象
The largest object associated with our solar system...
是奥尔特云
is the Oort Cloud.
这是个非常弥散的彗星云
And this is a very diffuse cloud of comets...
一直延伸到最近的恒星 半人马座α的半路上
that literally extends about halfway out...to the nearest star, Alpha Centauri.
半人马座α约在4光年之外
Alpha Centauri is about four light-years away.
天文学家估计坐上飞船
Astronomers estimate it would take the space shuttle...
需要数十万年
hundreds of thousands ofyears...
才能抵达奥尔特云的边缘
to travel around the outer edge of the Oort Cloud.
奥尔特云很昏暗 很遥远
The Oort Cloud is so dark and so distant...
我们真的无法直接看到它
that we really can't directly observe it...
不过我们知道彗星从四面八方过来
but what we do know is that comets come in...from every direction of the sky...
所以那必定是个球形的彗星云
so there must be a spherical cloud of comets...
距离我们遥远
far away from us.
奥尔特云的起源依然令人费解
The origins of the Oort Cloud remain puzzling.
一种理论认为其形成早于太阳系
One theory is that it was formed early in our solar system.
彗星争相奔向正在形成的太阳时
As comets fell in towards the forming sun...
它们就被弹入拉长的轨道
they were ejected into long orbits.
随着时间的推移 它们的轨道将其抛入巨大的云里
Over time, their orbits threw them out into a giant cloud.
非常遥远
lt's very far away...
充满了残余的冰
and it's filled with icy remnants...
基本上就是同样的状况
that havejust been left in basically the same state...
它们一直在那里徘徊
that theywere from right around the time...
此时我们的太阳系已经形成了
when our solar system formed...
就在45亿年前后
about four and a half billion years ago.
所以 可以说 它们是太阳系形成留下的古董
So they are, you could say, the archeological remnants...of the formation of our solar system.
宇宙里的东西有大有小
The universe is comprised of things both big and small.
不过太空中的大结构
But it's the large structures in space...
挑战着我们对宇宙运作的认识
that challenge our understanding of how the universe works.
尽管天文学家已经发现了许多重大的物体
Although astronomers have found many substantial objects...
发现更大对象的探索任重而道远
the quest to find even larger ones continues.
天文学家希望发现更大的行星
Astronomers are hoping to find new large planets...
新的超大星团
new huge super clusters...
更多地了解我们已经看到的东西
and learn more about the things that we've already seen.
随着更好的望远镜 更好的探测器 更新的探索
As technology improves with better telescopes...
所带来的技术进步
better detectors, newer surveys...
我们将能够看得更远
we will be able to see farther into space...
由此满怀信心去发现更大的东西
and therefore hopefully discover even bigger things...
超过我们已经了解的
than we already know about.
谢谢观赏
Thanks For Viewing